Draper Corporation Photographs 6612 P
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
- Contact prints from glass plate negatives, Series A:301-340: box no. 21-22, black and white photograph (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Item 331: Dutcher Street Residence, black and white photograph (Box 3, Folder 1)
    Printed in 1974 from glass plate negative no.A331. 1904- 1905. Image depicts an expansive two-family residence with three chimneys. The wooden structure has two stories and dormer windows in the attic. Shutters are at each window and the home features a wrap-around porch on the first level, and fenced balcony above the flat-roofed porch. Trees, shrubs and porch plants enhance the space between the sidewalk and front entry. Another home is partially visible in the left background. This residence was most likely constructed for Draper Company employees. 25 x 20.25 cm.
  - Item 334: Hopedale House (boardinghouse), black and white photograph (Box 3, Folder 1)
    Printed in 1974 from glass plate negative no.A334. 1904-1906. Image depicts a four-story wooden boardinghouse viewed from across the road. The building has one large and two smaller chimneys and a lightning rod. Shutters are installed at all windows (many of them closed). A front porch runs the length of the building although it is somewhat obscured in this view by bushes and trees. A sign "Hopedale House" can be seen above the porch roof. A fire escape is just barely visible on the left-hand end of the building. A lawn leads to an unpaved street beyond which (in the foreground) is open space and some trees. Trees surround the building in the background. Founders of the Draper Company, brothers George and Ebenezer Draper were responsible for creating the integrated, planned community of Hopedale with innovative employee housing and recreational spaces, in addition to employment. See Item 186 for another, earlier view of Hopedale House and Box 3, Folder 2, Item 343 and Item 344 for views from more of a distance. Original photograph by the Draper Company. 25 x 20.25 cm.
  - Item 335: Housing in Prospect Heights, Milford, Massachusetts, 1905; black and white photograph (Box 3, Folder 1)
    Printed in 1974 from glass plate negative no.A335. September 6, 1905. Image depicts a row of two-story brick buildings viewed from one end. These buildings were designed to accommodate two or more families. The building features include multiple chimneys, shutters at each window, and small lawns in front. A freestanding clothesline can be seen in the side yard next to the end building. Some open space is in the foreground, with some trees on the left. Prospect Heights was built as housing for Draper Company employees, but most houses in Prospect Heights were brick, as opposed to the wooden housing found in Hopedale, Massachusetts The houses are believed to have been designed by Peabody & Stearns. See also Box 12, Folder 4, Item 107 for a view of the end house and some houses on the right not visible here. 25 x 20.25 cm.
  - Item 336: Prospect Heights, units 7-14, Milford, Massachusetts, 1905; black and white photograph (Box 3, Folder 1)
    Printed in 1974 from glass plate negative no.A336. September 6, 1905. Image depicts a view of units 7 through 14 at Prospect Heights in Milford, Massachusetts The units are connected townhouse style, with eight separate entrances (two are double, the others are single), and are made out of brick. The entire building is two stories with a small window visible in the third story on each end. There are chimneys on each end, in the middle, and two in the rear. Another set of connected townhouses can be glimpsed on the right. Grass plots line the front, separated by walkways to each entrance. A large grassy area is in the foreground. Prospect Heights was built as housing for Draper Company employees, but most houses in Prospect Heights were brick, as opposed to the wooden housing found in Hopedale, Massachusetts The houses are believed to have been designed by Peabody & Stearns. See Box 2, Folder 1, Item 119 for what appears to be another view of these same units, and Box 3, Folder 2, Item 346 for what appears to be an almost identical view taken September 29, 1905. 25 x 20.25 cm.
  - Item 339: Housing in Prospect Heights, Milford, Massachusetts, 1905; black and white photograph (Box 3, Folder 1)
    Printed in 1974 from glass plate negative no.A339. September 6, 1905. Image depicts a group of two-story brick buildings designed to accommodate two or more families. The buildings' features include multiple chimneys, shutters at each window, and lawns. An open field is in the foreground. Prospect Heights was built as housing for Draper Company employees, but most houses in Prospect Heights were brick, as opposed to the wooden housing found in Hopedale, Massachusetts The houses are believed to have been designed by Peabody & Stearns. See Item 347, in this folder, for an almost identical view taken September 29, 1905, and Box 12, Folder 3, Item 99 for a broader view than seen here. 25 x 20.25 cm.
  - Item 340: Close-up view of housing in Prospect Heights, Milford, Massachusetts, 1905; black and white photograph (Box 3, Folder 1)
    Printed in 1974 from glass plate negative no.A340. September 6, 1905. Image depicts a closer view of a line of townhouses in Prospect Heights, two-story brick buildings designed to accommodate two or more families. These buildings feature Tudor-style timbering in the gables, roofed entrances (some single, some double), and shutters at all the windows (some closed). Based on the entrances this set of townhouses probably contained eight apartments. There are small lawns in front between the houses and the street. Open space is in the foreground. Prospect Heights was built as housing for Draper Company employees, but most houses in Prospect Heights were brick, as opposed to the wooden housing found in Hopedale, Massachusetts The houses are believed to have been designed by Peabody & Stearns. These houses can also be seen at the beginning of a stretch of homes in Box 12, Folder 5, Item 190. 25 x 20.25 cm.
- Contact prints from glass plate negatives, Series A:341-380: box no. 23-24, black and white photograph (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Item 341: Bancroft Memorial Library, 1905; black and white photograph (Box 3, Folder 2)
    Printed in 1974 from glass plate negative no.A341. September 6, 1905. Image depicts a single-story stone building with an arched doorway, situated on a street corner. It is partially hidden by trees. The library was donated to the town in 1898 by Joseph Bancroft, a Draper Company executive, in memory of his wife, Sylvia. The building was designed by Boston architect C. Howard Walker. It is constructed of Milford granite, and was modeled after Merton College Chapel at Oxford. On the left are marble sculptures that include an eagle, Greek goddess, two urns, and a bench. See Item 352, in this folder, for a clearer view of the library and sculptures. Original photograph by the Draper Company. 25 x 20.25 cm. Copy A.
  - Item 342: Bancroft Memorial Library, 1905; black and white photograph (Box 3, Folder 2)
    Printed in 1974 from glass plate negative no.A342. September 6, 1905. Image depicts a single-story stone building with an arched doorway, situated on a street corner. It is partially hidden by trees. The library was donated to the town in 1898 by Joseph Bancroft, a Draper Company executive, in memory of his wife, Sylvia. The building was designed by Boston architect C. Howard Walker. It is constructed of Milford granite, and was modeled after Merton College Chapel at Oxford. On the left are marble sculptures that include an eagle, Greek goddess, two urns, and a bench. See Item 352, in this folder, for a clearer view of the library and sculptures. Original photograph by the Draper Company. 25 x 20.25 cm. Copy B.
  - Item 343: Hopedale House, 1905; black and white photograph (Box 3, Folder 2)
    Printed in 1974 from glass plate negative no.A343. September 8, 1905. Image depicts a four-story wooden boarding house surrounded by other single- and multiple-story residences. The building has one large and two smaller chimneys and a lightning rod. Shutters are installed at all windows. A front porch runs the length of the building and a climbing vine provides shade. A sign "Hopedale House" can be seen above the porch roof. A fire escape is visible on the left-hand end of the building. Trees are planted between buildings and in the background view. Founders of the Draper Company, brothers George and Ebenezer Draper were responsible for creating the integrated, planned community of Hopedale with innovative employee housing and recreational spaces, in addition to employment. See Item 186 and Box 3, Folder 1, Item 334 for much closer views of Hopedale House and Item 344, in this folder, for the same view seen here but from more of a distance. Original photograph by the Draper Company. 25 x 20.5 cm.
  - Item 344: Hopedale House, 1905; black and white photograph (Box 3, Folder 2)
    Printed in 1974 from glass plate negative no.A344. September 8, 1905. Image depicts a four-story wooden boarding house surrounded by other single- and multiple-story residences. The building has one large and two smaller chimneys and a lightning rod. Shutters are installed at all windows. A front porch runs the length of the building and a climbing vine provides shade. A sign "Hopedale House" is barely visible above the porch roof. A fire escape is visible on the left-hand end of the building. Trees are planted between buildings and in the background view. Founders of the Draper Company, brothers George and Ebenezer Draper were responsible for creating the integrated, planned community of Hopedale with innovative employee housing and recreational spaces, in addition to employment. See Box 2, Folder 3, Item 186 for a much closer view of Hopedale House and Item 343, in this folder, for the same image seen here but from less of a distance. Original photograph by the Draper Company. 25 x 20.5 cm.
  - Item 345: House in Prospect Heights, Milford, Massachusetts, 1905; black and white photograph (Box 3, Folder 2)
    Printed in 1974 from glass plate negative no.A345. September 29, 1905. Image depicts a two-story brick building designed as a two-family residence. The building has four chimneys and two entrances in the front. A lawn, clothesline (on the left), and field are in the foreground. Other residences are in the background. Prospect Heights was built as housing for Draper Company employees, but most houses in Prospect Heights were brick, as opposed to the wooden housing found in Hopedale, Massachusetts The houses are believed to have been designed by the firm of Peabody & Stearns. 25 x 20.5 cm.
  - Item 346: Prospect Heights, units 7-14, Milford, Massachusetts, 1905; black and white photograph (Box 3, Folder 2)
    Printed in 1974 from glass plate negative no.A346. September 29, 1905. Image depicts a view of units 7 through 14 at Prospect Heights in Milford, Massachusetts The units are connected townhouse style, with eight separate entrances (two are double, the others are single), and are made out of brick. The entire building is two stories with a small window visible in the third story on each end. There are chimneys on each end, in the middle, and two in the rear. Grass plots line the front, separated by walkways to each entrance. A large grassy area is in the foreground. Other housing (without the gambrel roofs) are to the right. Prospect Heights was built as housing for Draper Company employees, but most houses in Prospect Heights were brick, as opposed to the wooden housing found in Hopedale, Massachusetts The houses are believed to have been designed by Peabody & Stearns. See Box 2, Folder 1, Item 119 for what appears to be another view of these same units, and Box 3, Folder 1, Item 336 for what appears to be an almost identical view taken September 6, 1905. 25 x 20.25 cm.
  - Item 347: Housing in Prospect Heights, Milford, Massachusetts, 1905; black and white photograph (Box 3, Folder 2)
    Printed in 1974 from glass plate negative no.A347. September 29, 1905. Image depicts a group of two-story brick buildings designed to accommodate two or more families. The buildings' features include multiple chimneys, shutters at each window, and lawns. An open field is in the foreground. Prospect Heights was built as housing for Draper Company employees, but most houses in Prospect Heights were brick, as opposed to the wooden housing found in Hopedale, Massachusetts The houses are believed to have been designed by Peabody & Stearns. See Box 3, Folder 1, Item 339 for an almost identical view taken September 6, 1905, and Box 12, Folder 3, Item 99 for a broader view than seen here. 25 x 20.25 cm. Copy A.
  - Item 348: Housing in Prospect Heights, Milford, Massachusetts, 1905; black and white photograph (Box 3, Folder 2)
    Printed in 1974 from glass plate negative no.A348. September 29, 1905. Image depicts a group of two-story brick buildings designed to accommodate two or more families. The buildings' features include multiple chimneys, shutters at each window, and lawns. An open field is in the foreground. Prospect Heights was built as housing for Draper Company employees, but most houses in Prospect Heights were brick, as opposed to the wooden housing found in Hopedale, Massachusetts The houses are believed to have been designed by Peabody & Stearns. See Box 3, Folder 1, Item 339 for an almost identical view taken September 6, 1905, and Box 12, Folder 3, Item 99 for a broader view than seen here. 25 x 20.25 cm. Copy B.
  - Item 349: Houses in Prospect Heights, Milford, Massachusetts, 1905; black and white photograph (Box 3, Folder 2)
    Printed in 1974 from glass plate negative no.A349. September 29, 1905. Image depicts a two-story brick building designed to accommodate multiple families. The building is the end unit of what is probably a string of attached townhouses. A street lamp and stone wall are in view along the street. Building features include chimneys and shutters at each window, and some Tudor-style timbers decorating the gable. The building has a small lawn that reaches to the sidewalk in front. Prospect Heights was built as housing for Draper Company employees, but most houses in Prospect Heights were brick, as opposed to the wooden housing found in Hopedale, Massachusetts The houses are believed to have been designed by Peabody & Stearns. 25 x 20.5 cm.
  - Item 350: Two houses in Prospect Heights, Milford, Massachusetts, 1905; black and white photograph (Box 3, Folder 2)
    Printed in 1974 from glass plate negative no.A350. September 29, 1905. Image depicts two two-story brick buildings designed to accommodate two or more families. Building features include chimneys and shutters at each window. Each residence has a small lawn that reaches to the sidewalk in front. A grassy field is in the foreground view. The house on the left is a two-family; the house on the right appears to be a multiple-family. Glimpses of similar housing can be seen behind these units. Prospect Heights was built as housing for Draper Company employees, but most houses in Prospect Heights were brick, as opposed to the wooden housing found in Hopedale, Massachusetts The houses are believed to have been designed by Peabody & Stearns. 25 x 20.5 cm.
  - Item 351: Town Hall, 1906; black and white photograph (Box 3, Folder 2)
    Printed in 1974 from glass plate negative no.A351. May 31, 1906. Image depicts a three-story stone building situated on a street corner. The building was designed by architect Fred Swasey of Milford and built in 1886; it appears to be in the Romanesque style, somewhat similar to that of H. H. Richardson. The building has two chimneys and a gabled roof with decorative ironwork running along the upper edge. There are three entrances at the front; two women and one man pose in front of the entrance between windows that read "Post Office." Another man leans against the building in one of the other entrances. A horse-drawn cart or wagon is partially in view on the street on the left; "Hopedale" is printed on the top edge of the cart. See also Box 12, Folder 4, Item 160. Original photograph by the Draper Company. 25 x 20.5 cm.
  - Item 352: Bancroft Memorial Library, 1906; black and white photograph (Box 3, Folder 2)
    Printed in 1974 from glass plate negative no.A352. June 6, 1906. Image depicts a single-story stone building with an arched doorway and windows. The library was donated to the town in 1898 by Joseph Bancroft, a Draper Company executive, in memory of his wife, Sylvia. The building was designed by Boston architect C. Howard Walker. It is constructed of Milford granite, and was modeled after Merton College Chapel at Oxford. On the left are marble sculptures that include an eagle, Greek goddess, two urns, and a bench; part of this group contains a fountain. See Item 317 for a view of the fountain; see Box 12, Folder 3, Item 77 and Item 78, and Item 342, in this folder, for other views of the library. Original photograph by the Draper Company. 25 x 20.5 cm.
  - Item 355: Tube Race, Field Day, 1906; black and white photograph (Box 3, Folder 2)
    Printed in 1974 from glass plate negative no.A355. August 18, 1906. Image depicts a bath house and residential buildings in the distance, viewed from across Hopedale Pond. Two men are in sitting in inner tubes in the water, but most people (including some women) appear to be in canoes. The heads of a few spectators are in the immediate foreground; other spectators can be seen on the dock outside the bath house. 25 x 20.5 cm.
  - Item 356: Boat Race, Field Day, 1906; black and white photograph (Box 3, Folder 2)
    Printed in 1974 from glass plate negative no.A356. August 18, 1906. Image depicts the start of the boat race at Field Day, with six rowboats, each with two male rowers, lined up to begin the race. Spectators are seated in boats along the shore in foreground and are also seen at the bath house on the opposite shore of Hopedale Pond. Note the two women with parasols in the boat on the right. 25 x 20.5 cm.
  - Item 357: High Jump, Field Day, 1906; black and white photograph (Box 3, Folder 2)
    Printed in 1974 from glass plate negative no.A357. August 18, 1906. Image depicts a man jumping over a pole (perhaps four feet high) that spans two side supports. He wears a shirt with the letter B in front. Officials stand by observing his jump. Spectators (mostly men) line both sides of the field. See Item 362, Item 378 and Item 379, in this folder, for other views of the high jump. 25 x 20.5 cm.
  - Item 358: Obstacle Race, Field Day, 1906; black and white photograph (Box 3, Folder 2)
    Printed in 1974 from glass plate negative no.A358. August 18, 1906. Image depicts men crawling into tubes of fabric that lay on the ground. Once at the far end, they need to stand up, fully enveloped in the tube, and make their way to the next obstacle or to a finish line. One man is fully enveloped and partially upright; two are in the middle of crawling through the tubes; one is just entering a tube. Officials and spectators (men and women) look on. See also Item 360, Item 376 and Item 377, in this folder. 25 x 20.5 cm.
  - Item 359: Cricket Match, Field Day, 1906; black and white photograph (Box 3, Folder 2)
    Printed in 1974 from glass plate negative no.A359. August 18, 1906. Image depicts men playing their field positions and a batter in place. A few spectators look on from beneath trees on the sideline on the right, barely visible. The field is large and well maintained. Residential houses are visible In the background. Founders of the Draper Company, brothers George and Ebenezer Draper were responsible for creating an integrated, planned community with innovative employee housing and recreational spaces and events, in addition to employment. 25 x 20.5 cm.
  - Item 360: Another Obstacle Race challenge, Field Day, 1906; black and white photograph (Box 3, Folder 2)
    Printed in 1974 from glass plate negative no.A360. Another Obstacle Race challenge, Field Day, Hopedale, Massachusetts Gelatin silver print, [1974], from a glass plate negative, August 18, 1906. Image depicts another part of the obstacle race: men climbing through wooden barrels and then across a series of ropes hanging above the ground from a wooden frame. Officials and spectators look on. See also Item 358, Item 376 and Item 377, in this folder. 25 x 20.5 cm.
  - Item 361: High Kick, Field Day, 1906; black and white photograph (Box 3, Folder 2)
    Printed in 1974 from glass plate negative no.A361. High Kick, Field Day, Hopedale, Massachusetts Gelatin silver print, [1974], from a glass plate negative, August 18, 1906. Image depicts a man in mid-air kicking right leg upward to hit an object hanging from a wooden frame. Officials and spectators look on. See Item 374, in this folder, for an almost identical view. 25 x 20.5 cm.
  - Item 362: High Jump, Field Day, 1906; black and white photograph (Box 3, Folder 2)
    Printed in 1974 from glass plate negative no.A362. August 18, 1906. Image depicts a man attempting to jump over a pole (about 4.5 feet high) that spans two side supports. Officials stand by observing his jump. Spectators line both sides of the field. See Item 357, Item 378 and Item 379, in this folder, for other views of the high jump. 25 x 20.5 cm.
  - Item 363: Pole Vault, Field Day, 1906; black and white photograph (Box 3, Folder 2)
    Printed in 1974 from glass plate negative no.A363. August 18, 1906. Image depicts a man participating in the pole vault. Having first propelled himself into the air with the use of a pole, he is pictured just clearing a horizontal bar held up by two supports. Officials stand by observing his vault. Spectators line both sides of the field; a tent is visible in the right background. 20.5 x 25 cm.
  - Item 364: Girls' Potato Race, Field Day, 1906; black and white photograph (Box 3, Folder 2)
    Printed in 1974 from glass plate negative no.A364. August 18, 1906. Image depicts three girls, each carrying a potato (possibly on a spoon?) and racing to their container (in the foreground) to place their potato without dropping it. Officials stand by observing the race. Spectators line both sides of the field; a number of girls in the background are probably about to participate, or already have participated, in the race. This event was most likely organized by the Draper Company and may have consisted entirely of Draper Company employees, or in this case, children of employees. See also Item 375, in this folder. 25 x 20.5 cm.
  - Item 365: Boating, Field Day, 1906; black and white photograph (Box 3, Folder 2)
    Printed in 1974 from glass plate negative no.A365. August 18, 1906. Image depicts the bath house and residential buildings on the opposite shore of Hopedale Pond. It is unclear if anything organized is ongoing, but several groups of people are enjoying rowing boats and canoes on the water, along with one man in an inner tube. Note the two women in the boat in the foreground, one holding a parasol. 25 x 20.5 cm.
  - Item 366: Canoe Tug-of-War, Field Day, 1906; black and white photograph (Box 3, Folder 2)
    Printed in 1974 from glass plate negative no.A366. August 18, 1906. Image depicts the bath house and residential buildings viewed from the opposite shore of Hopedale Pond. In the background, in front of the bath house, men in two canoes are pulling on each end of a rope, attempting to gain control in a tug-of-war. Several groups of people are watching from rowboats and canoes nearby. Note the boat in the left background, which seems to consist entirely of women. Spectators can also be seen in front of the bath house and on the shore on either side of the bath house. See also Item 367, in this folder, and Item 369, in this folder, for nearly identical shots. 25 x 20.5 cm.